

CONTACT

+44 (0) 7918 756467

+49 (0) 15171257736

matthewsangharad@gmail.com

www.angharadmatthews.com

EDUCATION

2016 - 2018

MA Devised Theatre and Performance Practices Arthaus Berlin/Rose Bruford London

2008 - 2009

Dance Training Program Rubicon Dance Cardiff

2002 - 2005

BA (hons) Theatre Design The Royal Welsh Collage of Music and Drama

2001 - 2002

BTEC Diploma Foundation Studies in Art and Design Pontypridd Collage, Wales

DATE OF BIRTH

03.08.1983

Angharad Matthews

THEATRE MAKER, PERFORMER, DESIGNER

PROFILE

Welsh Artist Angharad Matthews is a versatile freelance Performance Maker, Performer and Designer, working within the field of theatre, dance, film, and circus. She has worked extensively throughout Wales and Europe with companies including National Theatre Wales, National Dance Company Wales, NoFitState Circus, Gothenburg Opera, Volcano, Frantic Assembly, Company of Sirens and National Youth Theatre Wales.

Angharad was a founding member of Nurture Creative Dance Theatre based at Rubicon Dance, where she began developing her choreographic process with 'The Audition' funded by ACW.

Angharad now resides in Berlin where she completed her MA with Arthaus Berlin/Rose Bruford London. And is continuing to develop her ongoing practice, and creative collaborations.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Directing/ Teaching/ Workshop leading/Theatre games
- Costume Design/ Making/ Pattern Cutting/ Maintenance
- Hand and Machine sewing/ Appliqué & Textile art/ Dying and Distressing
- Research/ Sourcing /Buying
- Set Design/ Scenic Painting/ Scale Model Making
- Acting for Theatre/ Film/ Tv
- Devised theatre/ Collaborative theatre making
- Puppetry/ Mask work/ Clown/ Improvisation
- Stilt walking/ Street theatre/ Aerial Hoop
- Dance Theatre/ Choreography/ Movement direction

EXPERIENCE

2005 - 2020 - Theatre Designer/Maker/Supervisor - International

2008 - 2020 - Performer/Actress - International

2008 - 2013 - Workshop leader community arts - Wales UK

2016 - 2020 - Child carer and educator - Private tuition Berlin

2019 - 2020 - Physical theatre training workshop leader - Berlin

2019 - 2020 - Costume Assistant - Atelier Notre Facon- Berlin

LANGUAGES

English (First language)

German (A2.2)

Workshops

The Workshop Cardiff (2016)

Tokyo Space Dance (2013)

SKILLS

- Patience
- Adaptability
- Creativity
- Team Work
- Communication

OTHER INTERESTS

- Yoga
- Running
- Swimming
- Arts and crafts
- Reading

TV and Commercials

Hubspot (2020) Berlin - Commercial Smarva - (2020) Berlin - Commercial Allianz - Arthur Mebius – (2019) Berlin - Advertising Cinemagraph Flux FM Radio (2019) Berlin - Voice Stellan Stephenson (2019) Berlin/ Stockholm - Advertising Photos Netflix - Sex Education - Extra (2018)

REFERENCES

Theatre

Sean Crowley Head of Design RWCMD sean.crowley@rwcmd.ac.uk

Thomas Prattki, Founder and director Arthaus Berlin welcome@arthaus.berlin

Working with children

Jessica Hellman -Actress/Acting Coach lamdacentreberlin@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Productions

English Theatre Berlin - Director Grace Holme

You Me Human Tree (2020) - Costume Designer/Maker

Company of Sirens - Wales - Director Chris Durnall

- Souvenirs of a Killing (2020) Designer/Performer
- Twelve Cabins Twelve Vacancies (2019) Designer/Performer
- The Creature (2019) Designer/Performer/movement director

Uluak Teatro - Basque Country/Berlin

Maite (2019) - Costume Designer

Julia Van De hoff - - English Theatre Berlin/Ufer studios Berlin

Persephone (2019) - Deviser/performer

Cat Gerrard - Berlin/Basque Country

• Somewhere Maybe Here (2018 - 2019) - Costume Designer

Gothenburg Opera - Sweden - Choreographer Roy Assaf

• Sacre (2017) - Costume Designer

Nurture Creative Dance Theatre - Wales

• The Audition (2015 - 2016) - Director/Choreographer

National theatre Wales -

- Mission Control (2019) Costume Designer
- Before I Leave (2016) Costume Designer
- 150 (2015) Costume Designer
- The Gathering (2014) Costume Supervisor
- In Water I'm Weightless (2012) Co costume designer/Supervisor
- Little Dogs (2012) Costume Supervisor
- The Soul Exchange (2011) Costume Supervisor

Gwyn Emberton Dance - Wales

Shadows of a Quiet Society (2016) - Costume and Set designer

National Dance Company Wales -

- Tundra (2017) Costume Designer
- Profundis' (2016) Costume Designer
- Alternative Roots (2013) Costume Design Supervisor/Tutor

Walk the Plank - Wales Millennium Centre

• Ar Waith Ar Daith (2015) - Costume design/ Aerial Performer

Nofit state Circus - Director Firenza Guidi

- Bianco (2012 2015) Co Costume Designer
- Tabu (2008 2010) Co Costume Designer
- Immortal (2007) Co Costume Designer

(more detailed experience list 2005 - 2020 available on request)